-你干吗呢 -嘘
- What are you doing? - Shh.
有个烟雾警报器在叫
One of the smoke alarms is chirping.
我得找出来是哪个
I'm trying to figure out which one it is
这样我才能把电池换了
so I can change the battery.
找吧 这活非你莫属了
Well, if anybody can find it it's you.
你声音都变了
You s-sound horrible.
你为什么不 为什么不再去躺会呢
Why don't...why don't you go back to bed?
还有好多事儿没做呢
'Cause I've got too much to do.
我要做糕饼义卖会的手指饼
I've got to make the ladyfingers for the bake sale,
还要去下健身房
and I've got to go by the gym --
我昨天把手机落在那了
I left my phone there yesterday.
都交给我吧
I'll do all that.
要互相依靠嘛
We're a team.
累的时候 总要有个肩膀可以依靠
When one of us is weak, we lean on the other.
亲爱的 你不用为我做这些的
Honey, you don't have to do that stuff.
宝贝 你为我做了这么多
Honey, with all you do for me,
包括一周要去四次健身房
including going to the gym four times a week
让我对你的身体性趣昂然 今天就交给我吧
to keep me interested, I got this.
你今天不是要带人家看房子吗
Don't you have houses to show today?
他们 不来了
They...canceled.
别丧气啊 小可爱
Ohh, pumpkin.
说什么呢你
Are you kidding me?
这可是 交了好运了
It's...lucky.
这样我正好能在家好好照顾你啊
This way I get to stay here and take care of you.
好吧
Okay.
早啊
Hey!
你们好 邓菲先生 邓菲太太
Hey, Mr. and Mrs. Dunphy.
-你好 -海莉可以去上学了吗
- Hey. - Is Haley ready for school?
她快下来了
She's on her way down.
离我老婆远点
Don't get too close to my wife.
海莉告诉你们了吗
Haley told you about that?
那只是个下流梦罢了
It's just a dream.
天啊
Oh, god.
是了 是厨房那个在响
Okay, that came from the kitchen.
我怎么觉得是这里的
I-I thought it was in here.
你确定吗
Really?
你站在这听
Okay, you wait in here and listen for it.
我去厨房
I'm gonna wait in there.
至少我还能帮点小忙
I mean, it's the least I can do...
自从 你懂的
after...Well, you know.
我跟你一起去
I'm coming with you.
神啊 我真希望海莉能换个对象
Boy, I wish Haley would date some other boys.
你说什么 罗宾森[迪兰的姓]太太
What's that you say, Mrs. Robinson?
别闹了
Don't.
我只是觉得她
I just feel like she owes it to herself
不应该在一颗树上吊死
to see what else is out there.
迪兰天天在这里晃来晃去的
The way that Dylan's always hanging around here,
说不定一等海莉到结婚年龄
he's probably gonna try to marry her
他就想娶她了
the second she turns 18.
你怎么知道他们不配呢
Hey, you never know.
说不定他们是天造地设的一对呢
Maybe those two were meant to be together...
就像我们一样
like we were.
亲爱的 他们怎么能和我们比
Honey, Haley and Dylan are not us.
不 我觉得这个价格可以接受
No, I think that amount will be fine.
你们选了莉莉我都高兴疯了
I'm just happy you want Lily.
你们肯定会对她满意的
I-I think you're gonna be very happy with her.
就这样
Okay. Oh!
小卡 你不是把女儿给卖了吧
Cam? Did you just sell our baby?
没 但是你还记得那个上次那个
No, but do you remember that agent we met
给童星做代理的经纪人吗
that represents child actors,
就是那个说莉莉很有天赋
the one who said Lily might have what it takes
还给了我们名片的人?
and gave us his card?
不是被我扔了吗
Yeah, that I threw away.
我又捡回来了
That I fished out of the trash?
刚才就是他打电话
That was him on the phone they're shooting
说有个儿童家具的广告
a children's-furniture-store commercial today,
他们想让莉莉去拍!
and they want Lily!
我不是无缘无故把那张名片丢掉的
Look, I threw away that card for a reason.
拜托 会很好玩的
Come on, it'll be fun,
不但莉莉能出镜
and Lily will be on TV,
我们还能为她上大学存笔钱哪
and we can put the money in her college account.
我不要 我只想让我们的女儿
No, let's just let our daughter
有个正常的童年
have a normal childhood, huh?
晚了 莉莉已经上了基船了
I think that gay cruise has sailed.
只是一个广告而已嘛
It's just one commercial.
我不同意
I don't like it.
不行 绝对不行
No. No.
什么意思你
Oh, what, so that's it?
现在成了你说了算了
You're the parent with the final say?
凭什么 你不就赚两个臭钱吗
Why is that? Because you make the money?
你知道我不是那个意思的
It's not about that, and you know it.
我也没指望你能理解我们
I wouldn't expect you to understand us.
你一看就没明星范儿
You're not theater folk.
你也没
Neither are you.
你不就是有年夏天
You did "Godspell"
在谷仓里演过《上帝之语》嘛
one summer in a barn.
你顶多是个民间艺人
You're barn folk.
莉莉 要习惯被嫉妒
Get used to that jealousy, Lily.
燕雀安知鸿鹄之志哉
Ordinary people just don't understand us.
丹尼斯 速至终端收发站
Dennis to shipping and receiving.
好啊 杰克
Hola, Jack.
嘿 你们怎么到这儿来了
Hey! What are you guys doing here?
曼尼约了看医生
Manny had a doctor's appointment,
所以我们过来找杰一起吃午饭 他在吗
so we're gonna catch lunch with Jay -- is he there?
-在 他在里面 -好的
- Yeah, he's in back. - Okay.
你好啊 杰克逊
Good day, Jackson.
你好啊 曼纽尔
Good day, Manuel.
你还在开叉车呢
I see you're still forklifting.
更像是举着叉子
More like lifting the fork.
哥们 我正想说这笑话呢
Man, I was gonna say that joke!
真抱歉 但我今天得和老婆一起吃午饭
I'm sorry, but I gotta have lunch with my wife today.
我知道 但我必须娶她
I know, baby, but I had to marry her
否则她就拿不到绿卡
so she could stay in the country.
不
Oh, no!
我到哪再去找另外一个
Where am I gonna find another husband
上班还穿运动裤的老公呀
that wears sweatpants to work?
这是休闲服
Resort wear.
有点太休闲了吧
Maybe last resort.
我很高兴你们来找我吃午饭
Listen, I'm glad you guys step by for lunch,
因为你知道吗
'cause you know what?
我今晚要加班
I got to work a little late tonight.
不会吧 你忘了我们今晚的约会啦
No, not tonight. Did you forget our date?
没没 我就是逗你一下
No! No. I was kidding!
我完全不知道她在说什么
I had no idea what she was talking about.
歌洛莉亚 我的神呀
Gloria-god love her --
只要是个纪念日
likes to celebrate every possible milestone
她就都要庆祝一下
in our relationship --
我们的邂逅纪念日啊
Day we met...
我们的第一次约会啊
our first date --
那次我忘了 我们就大吵了一架
which I forgot, so we got in a big fight.
现在我们还得纪念吵架日
Now we commemorate the big fight.
我们可以情景再现一次
I thought we could re-create the day.
所有事情都按照第一次那天一样
Do everything that we did the first time.
太浪漫了
So romantic.
我也是这么想的
You know, that's exactly what I was thinking.
杰克真好人 他真的很喜欢曼尼
Jack is so nice. I think he really likes Manny.
我看他喜欢的是偷懒
What he likes is getting out of work.
等等 是曼尼在开吗
Wait a minute. Is that Manny driving?
是吗
Is it?
好吧 真是他
Yeah, it's him.
我可怜滴小宝贝 一天去两次医院
Ay, my poor papi. Two doctors in one day.
妈 我没事
Mom, I'm fine.
医生说我已经可以去上学了
The hospital said I could go back to school.
不行 你刚刚经历如此大劫
No, you suffered a traumatic experience.
我都快忘了
I barely remember it!
我只记得我把墙撞塌了
I remember crashing through the wall
然后就被救护车送去医院了
and the ambulance ride to the hospital.
没有什么救护车 是我送你去的医院
That wasn't an ambulance. I drove you.
-那警笛声哪儿来的 -是你妈在叫
- Then what was that siren? - That was your mother.
偶哪有那么大声
I was not that loud.
亲爱的 别的车都给你让路了
Cars pulled over, honey.
杰 很抱歉把你的墙撞塌了
Jay, I'm sorry about your wall.
不关你的事 是杰克的错
Wasn't your fault, was Jack's,
我已经把他解决了
and I've already taken care of him.
你把他杀啦
You killed him?
在美国杀人犯法
You can't kill people here.
我把他给炒了
I fired him.
但这只是个意外
But it was just an accident!
他又不是故意的
He didn't mean it!
那家伙就是个废物
The guy's a screw-up.
我早该把他炒了
Should have been gone months ago.
我们就不能再给他一次机会吗
Can't we just give him another chance?
什么"我们"
What is this "we"?
跟你们讲
Let me explain something to you people.
在家里 可以说"我们"
Here in this family, it's we.
在工作上 只有"我"
At work, it's me.
我的地盘我做主 说完了
My rules, my decisions...period.
这不公平
That's not fair!
你也生我的气吗
You mad at me, too?
米有 你说得对
No. You're right.
你的工作你说了算
It's your work.
何况 偶也不能你的气
Besides, I can't be mad at you --
因为今天是偶们的特殊日子呀
not on our special day.
亲爱的 我在想
Honey, I was thinking --
考虑到曼尼今天的遭遇
with what happened to Manny,
我们还是把我们的纪念日
maybe we better postpone our special day
推到下周末再庆祝吧
until next weekend.
不行 下周末是
No. Next weekend is the anniversary
人家第一次给你做饭的纪念日呀
of the first time that I cooked for you.
干啥呢 感冒小莱尔
What you doin', typhoid Clairey?
你怎么回家来了
Hey. What are you doing home?
你把感冒传染给她了 她就只好回家了
She caught your cold and had to come home.
我觉得该把你们俩隔离起来
I thought we should contain you two
省得把全家都传染了
and keep it from spreading through the house.
过来 抱歉啊宝贝
Come here. I'm so sorry.
没事
It's okay.
-手指饼干烤好了没 -还没
- Hey, did you finish my ladyfingers? - Not yet.
-我手机从健身房拿回来了吗 -也没
- Did you pick up my phone from the gym? - Not yet.
是烟雾探测器响吗 我以为你修好了呢
Is that the smoke detector? I thought you fixed that.
天啊 看来你倒是恢复得差不多了
Boy, you're really starting the sound like your own self.
你知道这让我想起什么了吗
You know what this reminds me of?
你小时候
When you were little
我们也常常靠在一起看肥皂剧
and we used to snuggle and watch soap operas together.
你还记得吗
Remember that?
一点都没变
Nothing's changed.
索尼娅还是那人的老婆
Sonya's still married to that guy.
-等等 -那个 谢顶的家伙
- One second. -The one with the...bad hairline.
-迪兰 -好 吧
- Dylan? - O...Kay.
天呐 我也好想你
God, I miss you, too.
只是感冒啦 小傻瓜
Oh, it's just a cold, silly.
你用不着乱想没有我的世界该怎么办
You don't have to conceive of a world without me.
没干吗 我正和我妈躺一起呢
Oh, nothing. I'm just in bed with my mom.
少抓狂了 你的梦不会成真的
Stop freaking out. It is not coming true.
沃恩夫人 我是菲尔·邓菲
Uh, Mrs. Vaughn? It's Phil Dunphy.
现在是下午三点半
It's about 3:30.
我知道您已经有新的选择了
Now, I know you said you'd moved on,
但是 您很喜欢的那套
but, um, there's been a significant price reduction
在沙利文峡谷的房子
in the, uh, house in Sullivan Canyon,
现在正特价呢
which I know you loved.
所以 如果您能重新考虑一下的话
So, uh, if there's any chance you might reconsider,
绝对不会让您失望的
I know you will not be sorry.
我随时恭候您 等您的电话
I can meet you anytime, so just give me a call.
随时 您想在哪里见面都行
Any -- anytime. I can meet you wherever that...
只要是您觉得合适的地方就行
...place is that you feel, uh, that would be best.
好吧 谢谢您 再见
Okay, thank you. Bye.
老爹
Dad?
嘿 小伙子
Hey, buddy!
你好吗 你在干吗
How are ya? W-what are you doin'?
防止细菌入侵
Keeping the germs off me.
你啥时候开始爱干净了
You care about germs?
我见过你跟鸽子玩亲亲来着
I've seen you kiss a pigeon on the mouth.
我们班过两天要去迪士尼乐园
My class is going to Disneyland in two days.
不能让老妈把感冒传染给我
I can't get mom's cold.
想法不错
Good plan.
我记得这个头盔
I remember this.
我老爸在古巴导弹危机时候买的
My dad bought it during the Cuban missile cisis.
我以前一直没机会戴 也许等一下
I never got a turn in that. You think maybe later I could --
可能吧
Yeah, maybe.
你大下午的怎么会在家
What are you doing home in the afternoon?
没啥大不了的
Oh, no big deal.
就是几个看房计划泡汤了
Just had a couple of showings fall through.
又泡汤了吗
Again?
你知道我的口头禅的
You know what I always say.
当然
Sure do.
不经历风雨 怎能见彩虹
Can't get back on that horse unless you fall off.
对啦
That's right.
太大声儿了
That's loud.
抱歉
Sorry.
这声音到底是哪儿来的
Where is that coming from?
更换烟雾探测器的电池
Changing the battery in a smoke detector
是男人要掌握的基本技巧
is what they teach you in Man 101,
所以说我每次听见这个声音
So, of course, every time I hear that noise,
就像听到了"哔哔 你不是纯爷们儿
all I hear is, "Beep beep -- you're not a man.
哔哔 你不是"
Beep beep -- you're not --"
你丫玩儿我吧
Really?!
老爹 能不能帮我开下书包
Hey, dad. Can you open this for me?
没问题 小伙子
Oh. Sure, buddy.
怎么了
What happened?
指甲断了
I broke a nail.
米奇尔 怎么了
Mitchell! What's up?
什么 什么怎么了
What do you -- what do you mean?
你 你刚才发来一条紧急短信
You -- you just sent me an urgent text,
叫我马上过来
saying to come right over.
是我发的 我用了杰的电话
That was from me, I used Jay's phone.
你的脸怎么了
Oh, what happened to your face?
只是一点擦伤
Oh, just a little scrape-up.
米奇尔 我要雇用你为我的朋友杰克
Mitchell, I'd like to engage your legal services
提供法律服务
in representing my friend Jack
起诉他的老板非法解雇
in a wrongful-termination suit.
没门儿 他回不来了
Forget it. He's not coming back.
米奇尔 不要接这个案子
Don't take the case, Mitchell.
我 我没准备接这个案子
I-I don't think I was gonna take the case.
好吧 那么基于这种情况
Fine. Then, under the circumstances,
我们没什么可谈的了
we have nothing further to talk about.
这是我对你说的最后一句话
These will be my last words to you.
敲敲
Knock knock.
是谁
Who's there?
好吧 我被你耍了
Okay, you got me.
你戏弄自己孩子不害臊是吧
I hope you feel clever tricking your kid.
米奇 你好吗
Hello, Mitch!
歌洛莉亚
Hi, Gloria.
祝贺祝贺
Congratulations!
祝贺什么
On what?
莉莉的拍广告的事
Lily's commercial.
不不 我们拒绝了广告商
Oh, no, no. We turned that down.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
小卡给我发了一张莉莉在化妆椅上的照片
Because Cam sent me a picture of her in her makeup chair.
不好意思 他干啥了
Uh, sorry. He what?
简直太让人兴奋了
Oh, it's so exciting.
你得记住这一天
You have to remember this day
这样你以后每年都可以庆祝
so that you can celebrate it every year.
好了大伙 我们10分钟以后开拍
Okay, folks, we're about 10 minutes from shooting!
明星就位了吗
Is talent ready?
是的 当然了
Yes, uh, she sure is.
听见了吗 莉莉 你是明星了
Did you hear that, Lily? You're the talent.
多神奇呀
Isn't that magical?
葡萄
Grapes.
是道具来着
And that is a prop.
好吧 我们这次真的该挂电话了
Okay, we're really gonna hang up this time.
数到三
On the count of three.
好了吗
Ready?
喂
Hello?
他居然给我挂了
I can't believe he hung up!
我要给他打回去
I'm calling him back.
拿给我
Hey, give me that.
天啊 那是杰西吗
Oh, my god. Is that Jesse?
他还没和安吉离婚呢
And he's still married to Angie.
给你说点有意思的东西吧
You know something else you might find interesting?
索尼娅现在嗜酒如命
Sonya is drinking,
因为她年轻的时候嫁了个蠢货
because she married a buffoon when she was young,
而她现在意识到她浪费了大好年华
and now she realizes she's wasted her entire life.
你能想象犯那样的错误会怎样吗
Can you imagine making a mistake like that?
当然 那一定 糟透了
Yeah, that must be...horrible.
她现在就是一个怨妇
Yeah, now she's just a bitter ghost of a woman,
心怀愤恨
filled with resentment.
你如果不考虑清楚便嫁作他人
But that's what happens when you commit to someone
最后的下场就是这样
before you see what else is out there.
搞什么呀
Seriously?!
她真是已经口不择言了
She couldn't have laid it on thicker.
"怨妇" "十足的蠢货"
"ghost of a woman"? "total buffoon"?
我又不傻
I'm not an idiot.
她就是在说她和我们老爹
She was talking about her and my dad!
可能索尼娅和她老公
Yeah, well, maybe Sonya and her husband
只需要 再努力一点
just need to... work a little harder.
他能把青春还给她吗
Can he give her those years back?
她本可以有所作为的
I mean, she could have been something.
她本可以环游世界
She could have traveled the world,
结交一些好男人的
been with fascinating men.
还有可能会事业有成
She could have accomplished things.
她现在每次看到他
That's all she thinks about now...
脑子里就只能幻想这些
every time she looks at him.
那不是老妈的围裙吗
Is that mom's apron?
围裙不分男女 都能戴
It's an apron. It's unisex.
很多世界级的大厨可都是男人
Some of the world's greatest chefs are men.
可是这围裙的胸部是突起的
But it's bumped out where the boobs go.
这声音越来越频繁了
That's happening more and more.
没注意
Hadn't noticed.
沃恩夫人
Mrs. Vaughn!
感谢你回电
Thanks for calling back.
是的 我正准备
Yeah, I was just about to...
我明白 我怎样才能改变你的
I see. Uh, is there anything I can say that will
好吧 非常感谢
All right. Well, thank you very much.
但如果 好吧 再见
And if -- o-okay. Goodbye.
又搞砸了一桩生意吗
Did you lose another one?
还未得到 又怎能算失去 对吧小子
Hey. Can't lose something you never had, right, pal?
那是门铃在响 老爸
That was the doorbell, dad.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
要是人家都不到你这买房子了怎么办
So, what happens if people stop buying houses?
我们是不是要去当童工
Are we all gonna have to get jobs?
只是个小坎而已 没什么大不了的
Just a little slump, buddy. Nothing I can't handle.
你好 我是罗恩
Hi, I'm Ron.
我是和克莱尔一起健身的
I work out with Claire at the gym.
快请进
Oh! Yeah. Come on in.
我是来送手机的 她昨天落在健身房了
I brought her phe back. She forgot it yesterday.
太好了 谢谢
Great. Thanks.
我是菲尔 克莱尔的老公
I'm phil, Claire's husband.
克莱尔从来没说过她结婚了
Oh. Uh Claire never mentioned she had a husband.
-幸会 -幸会
- Nice to meet you. - You too.
抱歉 我细嫩的手指烧伤了
Oh, sorry! I burnt my ladyfingers.
好安静啊
So quiet.
就像教堂里的图书馆
It's like christian "silence" reading room.
我挺好的
I'm fine.
我也挺好的
So am I.
好吧 俩倔强的小乖乖 我要出门了
Okay, my two stubborn burros. I'm going out.
曼尼 你要乖点
Manny, be a good boy.
杰
Jay...
我们待会见
Mm, I'll see you later.
你知道去哪找我的
I think you know where.
亲爱的
Honey?
你知道我刚刚在琢磨什么吗
You know what I was just thinking?
人们恋爱时
You know how when people are in love,
有时候会接对方的话茬
sometimes they finish each other's sentences?
就像
Like, um...
今晚我们要去
tonight we're going to...
逍遥快活
Have fun!
当然
Yes.
当我们到
When we get to...
一起之后
...gether later!
你根本就不知道你该去哪 没错吧
You have no idea where you're going, do you?
-请赐教 -除非把杰克请回来
- Tell me. - Hire Jack back.
-没门 -那你等着遭殃吧
-Forget it. -Your funeral.
莉莉 爸爸就在这
Okay, lily, daddy's gonna be right over here.
别怕哦
Okay.
顺便提一下 这或许或有点帮助
Oh, and, um, by the way, if it helps,
我列了一张单子 上面都是莉莉会做的事
I have a list of things Lily can do.
她会飞吻 还会像鸟一样挥舞双臂
She can blow a kiss, uh, flap her arms like a bird...
谢谢 我会记着的
Thank you. I'll...keep at in mind.
好的 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
小卡 小卡
Cam. Cam.
你是怎么进来的
How did you get on theet?
当然是走进来的 这里又不是米高梅
I walked on. It's not MGM.
这里只是一个床垫仓库
It's a warehouse behind a mattress store.
我真不敢相信你居然背着我干这事
I can't believe you went behind my back.
我们说好了
We agreed --
我们才没说好呢
We didn't agree on anything.
那是你一厢情愿
You agreed.
我们不一定每件事都要达成一致的
We don't have to agree on everything.
我不喜欢你上周买给她的书
I didn't like the book you bought her last week,
可是我也没阻止你读给她听呀
but I didn't stop you from reading it to her.
那书有什么不好的
Well, what was wrong with it?
那对饼干来说怎么会是个大日子 米奇尔
How was it a big day for biscuit, Mitchell? How?
好了 我们不是在说饼干的事
Okay, this isn't about biscuit.
我知道 这事关我们的女儿 莉莉
I know. It's about our daughter, Lily.
才不是呢 你想听真话吗
No, you want to know the truth?
我认为你这么做是为了自己 小卡
I think it's about you, Cam.
我认为你在利用我们的女儿
I think you're using our daughter
来完成你儿时的梦想
to fulfill some childhood dream of yours.
好了 家长们
Okay. Parents...
我们要开拍了
we're ready to start rolling.
我们拍摄的时候
Now, while we're doing the shoot,
吉姆和德布会一旁
Jim and Deb here will be doing
为孩子们配音
the kids' voice-overs into the mike --
就好像"猜猜谁在讲话"一样
kind of like "look who's talking".
太好了
Oh. That's great.
这里有太多重要人士了
There are a lot of important people here,
所以我不会在这和你吵
so I'm not gonna get mad,
可我对你的那些言外之意感到愤怒
but I resent the implication that I would do anything
你居然说我会做对我们女儿不利的事
that's not in the best interest of our daughter.
好了 开始试拍
Okay, let's try a take!
开机
And...action!
噢 不
Oh, no!
我们被困在这座家具贼贵的城里了
We are lost in a city of high furniture prices!
没人能保护我们不受这些价格的压迫吗
Ohh! Can no one protect us from these high prices?!
切 灯光有问题
Cut! Lighting problem.
稍等一会
One sec.
你随时可以向我道歉
You can apologize to me anytime you're ready.
-你开什么玩笑 -怎么了
- Are you kidding me? - What?
这个广告 涉嫌种族歧视
This commercial -- it's a big stereotype.
这叫做反讽
It's called "ironic."
不 难怪莉莉适合拍这个 她是亚裔
No, this is why Lily was perfect -- she's Asian.
她就是个道具
She's a prop.
这叫做天生我材必有用
It's called "niche casting."
别再跟我说这东西叫什么了
Stop telling me what stuff is called!
你简直被聚光灯蒙蔽了双眼
You're so blinded by the spotlight,
你根本看不见这里到底在拍什么
you can't see what's really going on here!
我们再拍一遍
Let's go again!
好了 开始了
All right. Here we go.
大家各就各位 拜托
Let's roll, please!
开拍
Action!
不 我们被困在一座
Oh, no! We are trapped in a city
家具贼贵的城里了
of high furniture prices!
没人能保护我们不受这些价格的压迫吗
Ohh! Can no one protect us from these high prices?!
看啊
Look!
在那儿
Over there!
那是恐龙战队[日本动漫形象]
It's save-zilla!
从婴儿围嘴到婴儿床
He's knocking down prices on everything
他将每件东西的高价都打倒了
from bibs to cribs!
婴儿游戏床打五折
Half off on playpens!
婴儿高脚椅也在降价
High chairs are low chairs!
对不起 打扰一下
Excuse me. Excuse me.
-打扰 打扰 打扰一下 -切
- Excuse me! Excuse me. Excuse me. - Cut!
有什么问题
What's the problem?
你不觉得这支广告
Well, don't you think this commercial
有一丁丁点种族歧视吗
just might be the teeniest bit racist?
我是说 恐龙战队
I mean, um, save-zilla?
这不是种族歧视 这是一种讽刺效果
It's not racist. It's satire.
不是 我懂 但是也许
No, I know, but maybe...
或许语气可以稍微轻一些
maybe we could just tone it down a bit.
或许口音不要那么重
Maybe not hit the accents so hard?
这支广告可是你同意拍的啊
This is the commercial you agreed to.
没错 我知道 我只是
Yeah, well, I know. I just...
我不能让我女儿拍这个
I can't let my daughter do this.
我们签了合同的
We had an agreement.
我也请来了本镇最棒的律师
Well, I also have the best attorney town,
放马过来吧
so do your worst.
对了 顺便说一下
And by the way,
莉莉是越南人 不是日本人
Lily is vietnamese, not japanese.
这其实差别还蛮大的
There's a big difference,
不过你是不会懂的啦
but you wouldn't know that,
因为你只想把这些孩子
because you're only interested in seeing these children
作为可轻易替换的模板而已
as interchangeable stereotypes,
你根本没把他们当人看
not human beings.
来吧 莉莉
Come on, Lily.
我们走
Let's go.
小卡
Cam?
小卡 抱错了
Cam, that's not...
你好 小家伙
Hi, buddy.
我们走
There we go.
我去找你妈
Going to meet your mother.
我自己想出答案了
Figured it out all by myself.
两年前 我们刚领完结婚证以后
Two years ago, we got our marriage license,
去了一家热狗摊吃热狗
we went to a little hot dog stand.
她说那是她这辈子吃过的
She said was the most romantic meal
最浪漫的一餐
she ever had in her life.
就是这个 对吧
That's it, isn't it?
没错 就是这个
Yeah, that's it.
记住这句话
Get this into your head.
你可以今后就这么冷漠地对待我
You can give me the cold shoulder the rest of your life.
但是杰克是回不来的了
Jack's not coming back.
知道吗 我可以容忍他的游手好闲
See, I could overlook the goofing off,
但你今天很可能会弄得个重伤
but you could have been seriously hurt today.
任何让我的孩子置于险境的人
Anybody puts my kid in danger
都不会有第二次机会 永远不会
doesn't get a second chance ever.
晚点儿见
I'll see you later.
你刚才说我是你的孩子吗
Did you just call me your kid?
我晕
Oh, geez.
你以前从没这么说过
You've never said that before.
我当然说过
Sure I have.
你当然是我的孩子
Well, of course you're my kid.
不然你认为呢
I mean, what do you think?
你去错地方了
You're going to the wrong place.
什么
What?
今天跟你们领结婚证无关
It's not your wedding license.
-那是什么 -初吻
- What is it? - First kiss.
不可能 你直说吧
No. Just tell me.
我是说 你和我妈的初吻
I mean, your first kiss with my mom.
我的天啊 你说的对
My god, you're right.
多谢啦
Thanks!
-码头 -谢谢
- The pier. - Thanks.
但也许索尼娅并没有做错
But maybe Sonya didn't make a mistake.
也许她是年轻时就遇到了心灵伴侣呢
Maybe she just met her soul mate when she was young.
不不不 这永远不可能发生的
No, no, no. That never happens.
看见没 她曾毅然抛弃自己的人生
See, she threw her life away,
而现在她想要解脱
and now she wants out.
好了 我们别扯这些有的没的了
Okay, let's cut the crap.
我们在谈的不是
We're not talking about some character
肥皂剧里的人物 对吧
on a soap opera here, are we?
是 你说的很对
No. No, we're not.
亲爱的 对不起
Honey, I'm sorry.
我不想伤害你的感情 但是
I don't want to hurt your feelings, but...
我已经想了很久了
I've been feeling this way for a really long time,
咱俩能彼此坦诚相待吗
and... Can we be honest with each other?
他的确是有点蠢
He's kind of a doofus.
我猜是吧 但是
I guess, but...
我还以为你就喜欢他这点呢
I thought you liked that about him.
不 我从没喜欢过
No, I never did.
相信我 亲爱的
Believe me, honey.
林子里的好鸟多着呢
There are many better options out there.
举个例吧
Like who?
我想想
I don't know.
比如说
Off the top of my head, uh...
送披萨的那个帅小伙怎么样
how about that cute guy who delivers the pizzas?
他还没长熟呢
He's like 18!
这有什么
So?
无视我接着聊
Don't mind me, ladies.
这是最后一个了
This is the last one.
我刚刚做出了一个艰难的决定
I've changed the batteries
给屋子里每一个烟雾报警器都换了电池
In every last smoke detector in the house.
老爸
Hey, dad.
我在网上找到个地方可以卖这风琴
I think I found a place online where I can sell this organ.
你能开车送我去黑市吗
Can you drive me to the black market?
黑市上卖的是器官不是风琴[同音多义]
I think they mean a different kind of organ, buddy.
宝贝 你为什么想卖掉那个
Sweetie, why are you trying to sell that?
以防老爸的生意继续缩水
In case things with dad's job get even worse.
说真的 我就不懂了
Honestly, I don't know why
你们怎么都这么大惊小怪的
everybody's making such a big deal.
我工作好好儿的
Everything's fine.
老天为什么要这样对我
It makes no sense!
我每一个都换过电池啦
I changed every one!
我还是打给我爸好了
I'm gonna call my dad.
不 不准求助他人
No, we're not calling anyone!
我能处理
I can handle this.
只需一根防狼棍即可
I just need the old burglar basher.
这不是你大学时候的拉拉队指挥棒吗
Is that your college cheerleading baton?
是棒子就能用来砸东西
Not when you're on the business end of it.
这下哔不出来了吧
Guess that one won't be chirping anymore, will it?
亲爱滴
Honey...
快去安慰安慰爸
Go after him.
不用 他发泄发泄就好了
Oh, no, he just needs to blow off some steam.
叫你个电池作怪
How's that for battery?!
妈 不管你乐不乐意
Mom, like it or not,
你们曾经海誓山盟过的
you made a commitment,
就算如今这誓言于你如过眼云烟
and maybe that doesn't mean anything to you anymore,
但为了这个家 你有义务挽救你的婚姻
but you owe it to this family to save your marriage
-再努力一回 -神马
- and give it one more try. - What?
末日到了 烟葱哥
End of the line, smokey joe!
爸爸也许是呆了点
Look, dad may be a doofus,
可他远比那个什么披萨幼齿男要好得多了
but he is 10 times better than any pizza-delivery boy.
快去安慰他
Go to him.
你不会以为
Did you --
轮到你冒烟了
I just detected your ass gettin' kicked!
得了
Okay.
亲爱的
Honey...
以为能逃过一劫 是吧
Thought I forgot about you, didn't you?
做梦
Nope.
菲尔 打住
Phil, no. Stop.
我不能让它在哔下去了
I gotta stop the damn chirping.
不是响声让你心烦
This isn't about the noise.
小亲亲
Sweetie...
你今天工作不顺心了
...you're having a bad day.
我都悲剧这一整个月了
At the end of a bad month.
我懂
I know.
你知道我有多害怕吗 克莱尔
You know how scary that is, Claire?
不 我不知道
No. No, I don't,
因为你从来不告诉我烦心事
because you never tell me the bad stuff.
你只对我说开心事
You only share all the good stuff.
我们不是说好要同甘苦共患难的吗
Honey, what happened to us being a team?
对吧 我们应该相互依靠才对啊
Right? We're supposed to lean on each other.
亲爱的
Honey...
我对你充满信心
I have faith in you.
一定是你的感冒害我流鼻涕
I must be catching your cold.
好了
Okay.
看开点
You know what?
我们买新的烟雾报警器去
Let's just get new smoke detectors.
我们去年刚换过一次
We already changed them out last year.
记得不 伙计 是你帮我换的
Remember, buddy? You helped me.
当然喽
Sure did.
等一下 拆下来的你拿去干吗了
Wait a minute. What'd you do with the old ones?
你叫我拿去扔掉的
You told me to throw them in the garbage,
于是我就拿去阁楼搭了个机器人
so I put them in the attic to make a robot.
是那些旧的在叫
It's the old ones.
电池快用完了
The batteries are dying,
声音是从通风口传进来的
and we can hear them through the vents.
多谢提醒 小子
You did it, buddy!
对不起晃到你了
I'm sorry.
我爱你
I love you.
那是我的功劳
I did that.
准是我订的披萨到了
Oh. That must be the pizza I ordered.
披萨 你叫披萨了
Pizza? You ordered pizza?
对啊 心血来潮想吃披萨
Yeah. I was just sort of in the mood, you know?
我们前几天刚吃过呀
But we had pizza a couple nights ago.
我知道 但我就是想吃
I know, but I had an urge,
心动不如行动嘛
and when you get an urge, you get an urge.
给我 我去付钱
Okay, here, I'll get it!
没事 宝贝 我去就行了
No, sweetie, I've got it.
不 妈 你总叫我做点力所能及的事
No, mom. You're always asking me to do things.
让我去 你坐好等着吃
I'll get it. Here, just sit back, relax.
我去拿披萨 别担心
I'll get the pizza. Don't worry.
我 我 真是 好吧 记得找零
I-I...really -- okay, get the change.
拿去
Here!
你再往我们家送披萨 我打断你的腿
And I think it's best you don't come around here anymore!